あんた達の基礎能力で 倒せない怪物は　ここには　いない。 足りないものがあるとすれば 敵を攻略するための手段を 戦いながら瞬時に考える力。
An x Indebted x Insect
自分達で手段を考え 怪物を捕らえなさいな。
Youpi's attack separated the Hunters.
あの子を強く育てるため
The central stairway was destroyed, with Youpi awaiting anyone still looking to ascend.
よっしゃ！ 「マリモッチ」　ゲット！ さまざまなタイプの敵と 戦わなければならない 「念」での戦闘
Behind him were Knuckle and Meleoron, who had barely managed to
make it to the second floor.
そこで　最も大切な戦闘技術とは 思考の瞬発力 まずは　考えることに慣れ それを限りなく 反射へと近づける
Below, the ones hit at closest range
by Youpi's attack were Shoot... This is bad.
このゲームそのものが そのための訓練
My leg's destroyed.
ここで　一番 捕らえるのに苦労するのは
...and Morel.
「バブルホース」だろうね それがクリアできれば
The rest is up to you.
第２段階　終了！
Knuckle...
集中力と回復力
Stupid tricks!
さて　では　これより 防御の修行に入る。
One attack by Youpi
それは…。 そうよ　ゴン。 あんたが使ってる技だわさ。
tore apart the Deep Purple puppets, but Morel had deliberately
positioned them with that in mind.
全て複合した応用技 「硬」！
They were just decoys?
体中のオーラを全て 体の一部に集め　攻撃する。
That resistance...
それ故　通常の攻撃を はるかに上回る威力がある。
This is more than smoke!
今から私が　この拳で攻撃する。 あんた達は これを全て受けて　防ぐこと。
The weapon was the only
thing that wasn't smoke?
察したようだわね　その通り。
Fool! You won't get away!
今まで通り 普通にオーラでガードしても 深いダメージを受ける。 では　どうする？ こっちも「硬」を使う。 半分　正解。
After using his own weapon as a decoy, Morel had no option left but to run. But...
これならば　よほど 念能力のレベルが違わない限り 無傷で済むだろうね。
Knuckle knew exactly what he had to do.
しかし…。 もし「硬」でガードした箇所以外に 攻撃がヒットすれば
Chapter 7 Bankruptcy!
即　破壊だわよ。 だったら 全身を「硬」にすればいい。
That... That punch was meant to send
him flying over the horizon.
矛盾してるけど。 その通り！ それを「纏」と「練」の応用技
The total is 590?
「堅」という。
Ten seconds feels like an eternity now...
全身を通常よりも　はるかに多い オーラでまとい　防御する。
Chapter 7 Bankruptcy applies additional damage
「硬」よりは　防御力が落ちるが これが最も実戦的な防御。
in the form of interest as time progresses
from the activation of the ability.
その状態を ずっと維持するのが　「堅」。
Lost sight of him...
そのまま　私のパンチを ガードして。
Damn you! The enraged Youpi
ん？　遅い…
returned to his senses because his multiple
eyes had caught sight of a shadowed form.
ゆっくりだったからって 体の力を抜いたわね？
With his right leg broken, Shoot unconsciously used his remaining
leg to stand on one of his own fists.
「堅」まで解いてたら 顔　つぶれてたわよ。 今のは「硬」のみの力。 この威力に拳本来の スピードと破壊力を乗せれば
Despite that he had never attempted it before, Shoot realized that this was his ultimate technique.
数十倍にもなる。 最初は今みたいに ゆっくり打つけど
And he had no clear reason
to cover his right eye.
いつかは言わない。
He was just enjoying the fact
「堅」の状態で できる限り耐えてみなさいな！
that he continued to gain strength
while the situation deteriorated.
う…　うぅ…。 うぅ…。 うっ…。
Fueled by adversity itself, Shoot took flight.
よし　開通！ 「堅」の修行だ！
His tremendous speed and vigor succeeded in forcing Youpi to
concentrate on defense for a few seconds.
くぅ…。 よし　３０分経過！
to help the others.
この１か月で だいぶ　タフになったわね。 数字の３！ 数字の３！ ピンポン！　一瞬　キルアが早い。
Shoot, Knuckle...
う！ さて　今日から　実戦の修行に入る。 ん？
Once we finish this, first thing we do
is drink ourselves silly with good alcohol.
「堅」！ この状況は 攻撃力５０　防御力５０。 つまり　お互いが「堅」の状態では
That's the only way I can get you guys
to let me give you a big hug.
いくら戦っても　お互いに 大きなダメージは与えられない。
The debris cloud raised by the destruction
さて　どうする？ 「硬」を使う！ バカタレちゃん！
was the perfect cover for Morel to expand
his smoke aura throughout the palace
「硬」以外のとこ突かれちゃったら どうすんの！
so he could monitor the course of the battle.
「凝」を使う。 正解！
Morel's objective was the throne room.
攻撃力５０　防御力５０から 攻撃の瞬間に 右拳の攻防力を７０ 全体を３０に。 このように「凝」を使い 状況に応じて 攻防力を変化させる。
When Youpi destroyed the central stairway, Gon and Killua evaded the attack
and changed direction.
左足　攻防力８０　全体２０！
the east tower's second floor to the central
tower's third floor, where the throne room was.
頭　攻防力６０　全体４０！ これを３０分間　一日３回
Upon hitting the ground, they passed
Ikalgo in the courtyard as he headed
今までのメニューに加えて行う。
for the elevator underground.
それと…。 ゲッ！ 組み手の修行にも入る。 さっき教えた「流」を使って ゆっくりでいいから やってごらん。 受ける側も 相手の攻撃力を見極めた上で 「流」を使って きちんと防御すること。
His ability that let him control corpses
like part of his own body, Living Dead Dolls, granted him
the use of multiple sets of eyes, which had allowed him to
dodge Dragon Dive unscratched.
じゃあ　俺からな。 右足　攻防力５５
In the corner of his eye, Killua spotted
右足　攻防力６０…　かな？
two soldier Ants in the direction
左手　攻防力６０
that Ikalgo was headed.
２か月ぐらい 毎日　これを続けていれば
In the next moment, Killua had taken off.
自分の系統だけを 修行してもいいんだけど…。
Killua?
例えば　強化系の場合
Why is he heading toward the elevator?
隣の変化系や放出系なども
What am I doing?
バランスよく鍛える。
What's wrong with me?
そうすると 自系統の覚えも早くなるの。 ９！ ピンポン！　引き分け。
It was only natural that Killua would
be surprised by his own actions. He was the one
やるね　キルア！ そっちこそ。 それじゃ　始めましょうか。 オス！
who had instructed the others
to stick to their own tasks.
今日やるのは強化系の修行。 そのレベル１　石割り。
At that point, Killua's mind completely froze.
これは　かなりキツいぜ インパクトの瞬間に 持ってる石の周りの攻防力を １００にするだけなのに 回数を重ねるごとに 「念」の精度が落ちて来る あっ！　割れちゃった！ 持ってる石が割れたら終了！ クソ！ あっ　クソ！　失敗か。
However, while his mind panicked, his body continued to move efficiently, keeping aura usage to a minimum, while swiftly and accurately
よし！　じゃあ　次は 変化系の修行しようぜ。 まぁまぁ　慌てなさんな。
gauging the two soldier Ants' abilities
and movements, and halting them.
またか。 最近　ずっとだね。 それだけ　２人とも　「凝」が 身について来たってことだわさ。
Only Ikalgo and one other
saw what had happened.
えっ？ えっ？
Damn...
パは 内臓を破壊するための「掌」。
What have I
チョキは　局部破壊を狙う「指」。
done?
残り１０枚のうち ７枚は　所在も判明している。 手に入れたも同然だ！
Killua, I owe you one.
ただ　ツェズゲラが率いる連中も 同程度の指定カードを 持っているらしい。
After he realized what he'd done,
a tangle of emotions
恐らく　奴らとの直接対決が 最後のハードルだろう。 しかし　スペルカードの質と量は こちらが圧倒的なはず。
had left Killua lost in confusion, until Ikalgo's words woke him.
おぉ！ １つ　俺からも　いいか？ ５年　長かったような 短かったような…。
By the time the two Ants' remains hit the floor, Killua was already moving on.
ここで　皆さんに言っておかねば ならないことがある。
Flutter?
俺は　ボマーだ。
Something's wrong.
えっ？ 何だ？　ボマー？ おい　一体　何を…。 まぁまぁ　聞いてくれ。
At either end of the hall leading to the
elevator underground were the servant quarters, which soldier Ants currently occupied.
君達全員の体に　爆弾を仕掛けた。 えっ！ 何だと!? 一体　どうやって！ 貴様　ふざけるなよ！ まぁ　冷静に聞いてくれ。 ぐっ！　うぅ！
Ikalgo raced past the two Ants, and at the moment when he reached the elevator, the doors at both ends opened simultaneously.
やれやれ　説明の順序が 狂ってしまったな。
From the doors appeared...
ご覧のように　手でつかんだものを 爆破できる。
Cheetu...
だが威力は　さほどない 彼も一命は取り留めたようだ。
Brovada!
だが　皆さんに仕掛けた 爆弾が爆発すれば 確実に死ぬ。 あっ　あぁ…。 爆弾？　おい　どこだ!?
After seeing Flutter, Welfin had hidden because he'd smelled
that something was wrong.
では　これから 爆弾を解除する方法を教えよう。 まず　どうやって 爆弾を仕掛けたのかだが
That was too fast. Once they spotted the enemy,
the two soldiers raised an alert.
それは　ターゲットの 爆破させたい箇所に触れながら
Right afterward, they were killed.
あるキーワードを言うことで 仕掛けられる。
The time between the intruder's
return down the hallway
キーワードは…。 「ボマー」。
and Flutter's appearance was too short!
) )
Which means they must have passed
one another in the hallway.
これを解除するには 俺の体に触れながら 「ボマー捕まえた」と 言わねばならない。
Then why were the soldiers killed, but not Flutter?
ただし　俺には　もう一つの能力 「リトルフラワー」がある。
Is Flutter on the enemy's side? Meaning...
これを使い　俺に 触れようとする者を阻止する。
He's a traitor! Is he acting on his own, or...
十分に気をつけて 爆弾の解除を目指してくれ。
Is it Hagya's... Or rather...
以上！ はっ！
Leol's orders?
なぜ　ペラペラと 自分の能力について話をしたか それが　爆弾の発動条件だからだ。
This is pathetic.
そこで　カードも仲間も
When he needed me most, I wasn't there.
一斉に集まる この日を狙っていたわけだ。
And I call myself a Royal Guard?
さて　ここで　提案だ。
I don't even know where the King is.
君達の命と指定ポケットカード ９０種を交換したい。
And I call myself a Royal Guard?
要求に応じてくれれば 俺は　もう一つの解除法で
No.
皆さん　全員の爆弾を 一斉解除する。
I am a failure!
何もしなければ　カウンターが 「０」になった時点で　みんな死ぬ。
It's that simple...
全員で　よく相談して決めてくれ。 取引場所は バッテラ氏所有の古城。
Pouf's loyalty made him both strong and weak.
誰でもいいが　１人で来ること。 お前さん　頭は確かか？
The ideals he prioritized were
unyielding and absolute.
落ち着けよ　興奮すると カウントダウンが早まるぜ。
Pouf, the former Royal Guard. Now, Pouf...
その数字は　心拍数と リンクしてるんだからな。
Useless Pouf... You utter fool.
何!?
You failure of a Royal Guard!
ブック。
Where will you go now?
しまった！　うっ！
You have no idea?
ハハハハハ！ それでは　再会を祈る！ 「リーブ」オン！
And if the King isn't there, then you'll be more useless
than scum, won't you?
ゲーム外に逃げやがった！ 俺達も追いかけよう！
No, useless Pouf...
待て！　そのまま出たら バインダーのスペルカードが 消えちまう！
You just refuse to accept reality.
落ち着け！　今　追いかけるのは 得策ではない！ 俺達が　なぜ徒党を組んだのか 忘れたのか！
You don't want him spending
time with that woman!
戦闘力に欠けてたからだろ！ この中に　奴を倒す自信のある 使い手などいるのか!?
His emotions were directed at
the King as well as himself.
無理だな　あの念能力 かなりの実力者だぞ。
An absolute King, feeling concern for a lowly human...
仮に　ここにいる全員が 一斉にかかって行ったところで
Visiting the room of a lowly human by choice...
「リトルフラワー」とやらで 返り討ちだろう。
It is unforgivable!
クソ！ やっと　ここまで来たのに…。
But...
まずは　全員の意思を 統一する必要がある。
That's probably where the King is...
カードを渡すか それとも奴と戦うか。 カードを渡してくれ。 頼む。
Before I came here, I knew that much.
ジスパーには　もう時間がない…。
I didn't fail as a Royal Guard because
I didn't know the King's location.
意外だな。
Yes, Pouf, you traitor, lower than scum.
てっきり ニッケスが来ると思っていたが。 こっちもな　まさか１人で…。
You are now a mere bug!
うっ！
You can no longer expect anything of yourself.
サブとバラ ボマーのメンバーさ。
Nor are you allowed, then,
to expect anything of the King!
早速だが　指輪を貰おうか。
I can only work for the King...
うっ…。 どうした？
For the King... For the King...
まだ　渡せない というより　結論が出ていない。
For the King! For the King! For the King! For the King!
特に　ニッケスは 瀕死のジスパーのために
For the King!
「大天使の息吹」の カードをくれと言っている。 ふざけるな！ このままだと　共倒れだぞ。 あっ？ あんたが思っている以上に みんな混乱している。 結論が出ないまま タイムオーバーで全員　爆死したら
Instead, his emotions, bordering on fanaticism, prevented him from thinking clearly in the
seconds after he arrived in the throne room.
だが　俺なら…。 「俺なら うまく仲立ちできる」とでも？
I must go to the King.
いかに　冷静でイカレているか 相手に理解させるのがコツだ。
Yo.
プレーヤーを殺して 指輪を奪っても
He goes straight to the King without a glance.
指定ポケットのカードデータは 消えない。
Unfortunately, you've been surrounded.
まっ　どうせ　お前は カードを持ってないだろうがな。
What must I do
あっ！
Oh, I'm not letting you out.
ふざけるな！　「リーブ」は とても貴重なんだぞ！
Spiritual Message.
あっ！ ボマーは　３人いるのさ。 まっ　ゲンスルーが本体なら
That's Morel's Smoky Jail...
俺らは　備品みたいなもんだが。 ３人が右手親指を合わせて キーワードを言うと
The ability he's using to separate
Pouf from the King.
爆弾は　消滅する。 それが　もう一つの解除法だ。
If the third floor of the tower
is surrounded by smoke, the King and Pitou aren't there.
まぁ　いいや。 俺は　正規のルートで ゆっくり戻るから
Where are they?